Finding Aid for the Olive Percival Papers LSC.0119
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 3. Correspondence
  - Undated notes., Item 25 (Box 1)
    - b. Small folder "A gift on Valentine's Day"
      - red and silver on white "Jane Wright is her pretty name-" written by OP in ink below verse inside folder.
    - c. White folder with picture of little girl holding kittens on front.
      "Jane" written in ink by OP on front, note inside.
    - d. Note written in ink on white paper to "Jane dearest" signed "Olive".
      [Has been used by someone else for written memos on the back.] N.D. but "10 P.M." under signature.
    - e. Note on small white paper, in pencil, to "Jane dear" signed "O". at top., Dated Monday Eve.
    - f. Note on folded sheet blue paper, in ink, no salutation, signed "Olive".
    - g. Letter written in ink, addressed to "Jane dear" and signed "Olive". Note paper., dated "Sunday Night & almost Monday Morning"
  - Envelope (small) postmarked Pasadena, addressed in ink by OP to Jane Wright, closed on back with a small orange heart., Feb 11, 1932; Item 26 (Box 1)
    Contains valentine made of gold paper, Cupid, bird and flowers.
  - Letter to "Elizabeth dear" [Mrs. Elizabeth Wright Clark] from Olive Percival., [1932 Mar.3.]; Item 27 (Box 1)
    First sheet bears decorative cut-outs pasted on (dog, and potted tree). ALS, 2 p. Cover postmarked Los Angeles.
  - Envelope postmarked Los Angeles addressed to Jane Wright, containing valentine made of flowers, hearts, etc. pasted on folder., Feb. 12, 1934; Item 28 (Box 1)
    OP disguised her handwriting on this, except on return address.
  - Birthday letter addressed "Jane dearest" signed "Olive"., [1935 Mar.]; Item 29; ALS, 2 p. blue note paper. (Box 1)
  - Picture postcard "The Queen's Dolls House", postmarked Los Angeles, Sept. 25, 1935.; Item 30 (Box 1)
    Written in ink by OP, addressed to Mrs. Geo. V. Wright.
  - Correspondence card written, ink, by OP, addressed to Mrs. George V. Wright., 1935 Nov. 8; Item 31 (Box 1)
  - Letter addressed to "Dear Jane" signed "Olive"., 1936 Feb. 3; Item 32; ALS, 1 p. note paper folded. (Box 1)
  - Picture post card postmarked Los Angeles, with print of painting in Metropolitan Museum on front. Written in ink by OP, addressed to Mrs. George V. Wright., Feb. 17, 1936; Item 33 (Box 1)
  - Government post card postmarked Los Angeles, Written in ink by OP and addressed to Mrs. George V. Wright., Sept. 3, 1936.; Item 34 (Box 1)
  - Small envelope postmarked Los Angeles, addressed in ink by OP to Jane Wright., Feb. 13, 1939; Item 35; Sealed with silver heart. Contains valentine, verse written in ink by OP. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence card postmarked Los Angeles, written, ink, by OP, addressed to Mrs. George V. Wright., May 8, 1939; Item 36 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence card postmarked Los Angeles, written, ink, by OP, addressed to Mrs. George V. Wright., July 6, 1939; Item 37 (Box 1)
  - To "Jane dearest," signed "Olive.", 1939 July 17.; Item 38; ALS, 2 p. (Box 1)
  - Thanksgiving Eve.", 1939 "; Item 39; ALS, 2 p. (Box 1)
    To "Jane darling," signed "Olive."
  - 1940 Dec. 27., Item 40 (Box 1)
    To "Dearest Jane," signed "Olive." ALS, 2 p. Cover, postmarked Los Angeles, Dec. 28, 1940.
  - 1941 Feb. 19., Item 41; ALS, 2 p. (Box 1)
    To "Jane dearest," signed "Olive."
  - Small folder with Easter poem addressed in ink "Dearest Jane" signed "Olive Percival/, 1942."; Item 42 (Box 1)
    In envelope, addressed in ink, "This is for Jane/Easter Morning!"
  - Correspondence card postmarked Los Angeles, Oct. 9, 1942.; Item 43 (Box 1)
    Written by OP in ink, addressed to Mrs. George V. Wright.
  - [n.d. "Sunday"], Item 44 (Box 1)
    To "Dear Jane dearest" signed "Olive." ALS, 1 p. 2 clippings enclosed. In cover postmarked Los Angeles, Nov.23,1942.
  - [n.d. "Tuesday"], Item 45 (Box 1)
    To "Jane dearest," signed "Olive." ALS, 2 p. In cover postmarked Los Angeles, Jan. 13, 1943.
  - Picture postcard postmarked Portland, Oregon, Mar. 15, 1943.; Item 46 (Box 1)
    Photograph of Mt. Washington on one side. Addressed to Miss Olive Percival, and signed "L.F."
  - Birthday card to "Jane darling," from "Olive.", Item 47 (Box 1)
    In cover postmarked Los Angeles, Mar. 22, 1943.
  - [n.d. "Thursday Noon"], Item 48 (Box 1)
    To "Jane dearest" from "Olive." ALS, 1 p. In cover postmarked Los Angeles, Apr. 6, 1943.
  - Picture postcard postmarked Los Angeles, with picture of Church Square, Rye., July 12, 1943; Item 49 (Box 1)
    Written in ink by OP, addressed to Mrs. George V. Wright.
  - [n.d. "Tuesday Evening"], Item 50 (Box 1)
    To "Jane dearest," signed "Olive." ALS, 1 p. Includes another page signed "Olive." Both in cover postmarked Los Angeles, Apr. 5, 1944. [Envelope has been used by someone else for notes.]
  - [n.d. "Sunday"], Item 51 (Box 1)
    To "Very dear Jane," signed "Olive." TLS, 1 p. Has short poem, typed, on small paper pinned to left upper corner.
  - Mabel R. Gillis, State Librarian to Mrs. Florence M. Kreider., 1949 May 2; Item 52 (Box 1)
    Acknowledges gift of OP book, and bookplates. With cover. TLS, 1 p.
    Missing, 6-25-82.
  - Rachel [?] to Florence [Kreider] acknowledging receipt of bequest., [1946 Feb] 25.; Item 53 (Box 1)
    TLS, 1 p. Cover, postmarked Santa Barbara Feb. 27, 1946.
  - Laurena Alliot to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Aug.26.; Item 54 (Box 1)
    Acknowledges receipt of book of verse. Cover, postmarked Los Angeles Aug. 11, 1946.ALS, 1 p. folded note.
  - Roxy [Mrs. Everard Bierer] to Olive., 1944 Jan.9.; Item 55 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded. Cover postmarked Salt Lake City, Jan. 9, 1944.
  - Roxy C. Bierer to Olive., 1945 Apr.4.; Item 56 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Salt Lake City, Apr. 5, 1945.
  - Phil & Bernyce Boyden to Miss Percival., [1944 Nov] 20.; Item 57 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded. Cover postmarked Rockford, Ill, Nov. 22, 1944.
  - F. R. Burnham to Olive., 1942 Jan.14.; Item 58; TLS, 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Ruth W. Burnham to Mrs. Kreider, acknowledging receipt of book of poems., [1946] Dec. 13.; Item 59 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Pasadena Dec.15, 1946.
  - Luella H. Butts to Mrs. Kreider, acknowledging letter., 1945 June 26.; Item 60 (Box 1)
    Cover postmarked Norwalk, Calif. Jun. 27, 1945. TLS, 1 p.
  - Luella H. Butts to Mrs. Kreider, acknowledging receipt of package., [1945]; Item 61 (Box 1)
    TCS, postmarked Norwalk, Calif. Jul. 5, 1945.
  - Luella Hawk Butts to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 Sept.6.; Item 62 (Box 1)
    TL, 1 p. folded. Cover postmarked Norwalk, Calif. Sep. 6, 1945.
  - Luella Hawk Butts to Mrs. Kreider, acknowledging book., 1946 Aug.15.; Item 63 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded. Cover postmarked Norwalk, Calif. Aug. 16, 1946.
  - Charles [Wakefield Cadman] to Florence [Kreider] acknowledging book of poems., 1946 Aug.11.; Item 64 (Box 1)
    Cover postmarked Los Angeles, Aug. 12, 1946. ALS, 1 p.
  - Dorothy H. Cohn to Mrs. Kreider, acknowledging packages., 1946 Apr.9.; Item 65 (Box 1)
    ALS, 2 p. Cover postmarked San Francisco Apr. 11, 1946.
  - Adelaide [Blanchard Crandall] to O.P., 1926 Jan.6.; Item 66 (Box 1)
    Thanks for gift. ALS, 6 p. Cover. OP has noted, ink, on cover: "(Adelaide Blanchard Crandall/Artist-Teacher-/Md. L. B. C., Teacher of/ Lloyd-then a Bee Specialist-/ State College)
  - Adelaide [Crandall] to [Olive Percival]., [1942 Dec.11]; Item 67 (Box 1)
    Christmas card and ALS, 1 p. note. Cover.
  - A.B.C. [Adelaide Blanchard Crandall] to Olive., [1943]; Item 68 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. enclosing small crayon drawing on brown paper. Cover.
  - Adelaide [Crandall] to Olive., 1944 Jan.17.; Item 69 (Box 1)
    Thanks for gift. ALS, 1 p. Cover.
  - Adelaide Blanchard Crandall to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 Apr.10.; Item 70 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Mansfield, Conn. Apr. 11, 1945.
  - Adelaide Blanchard Crandall to Mrs. Kreider, acknowledging book of poems., 1946 Aug.16.; Item 71; Cover. ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Bertha H. Davis to Olive., 1944 Jan.24.; Item 72 (Box 1)
    Thanks for gift. ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Buda, Ill. Jan 24, 1944.
  - Bertha [Davis] to Olive., [1944 Sept.]; Item 73; ALS, 3 p. Cover. (Box 1)
  - Bertha H. Davis to Olive., [1944 Dec.]; Item 74 (Box 1)
    ALS, 2 p. Cover postmarked Buda, Ill. Dec. 6, 1944.
  - Bertha Humphrey Davis to Mrs. Florence Kreider., 1945 May 16.; Item 75 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Sheffield, Illinois. Cover.
  - M.F.D. [Mary Denton] to "My dear Friend"., [1914 Sept.10.]; Item 76 (Box 1)
    Re: possible job for OP. ALS, 3 p. folded. Pencil. In cover 10-9-14.
  - M.F.D. [Mary Denton] to "My dear friend"., 1921 Aug.29.; Item 77; ALS, 2 p. Kyoto. Cover. (Box 1)
  - Eda [Dessau] to Olive., 1945 Jan.8.; Item 78 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Los Angeles, Jan. 9, 1945.
  - Eleanor Pearson Dow [Mrs. Arthur] to Miss Percival., [1910 Feb.5]; Item 79 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p folded note. Cover postmarked New York, Feb. 5, 1910.
  - Hildegarde F. to Florence [Kreider] acknowledging books., 1946 Aug. 24; Item 80 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Altadena, Aug. 27, 1946.
  - Elizabeth H. Fairley to Miss Percival., 1943 Dec. 20; Item 81 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded encl. Christmas greeting card. Cover postmarked Los Angeles, Dec. 21, 1943.
  - Elizabeth H. Fairley to Miss Percival., 1944 Nov. 5; Item 82; ALS, 3 p. (Box 1)
  - Eleanore Foss to "Cousin Olive.", 1944 Dec. 7; Item 83 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked Pittsfield, Mass. Dec 7, 1944.
  - Ann [Annie Foote Foss] to Olive., [1945] Jan. 28; Item 84 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked Pittsfield, Mass. Jan 29, 1945.
  - Annie F. Foss to Mrs. Kreider., [1945] June 5; Item 85 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked Pittsfield, Mass. June 6, 1945.
  - Annie Foss to Mrs. Kreider., [1945] June 20; Item 86 (Box 1)
    Thanks for books. ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked Pittsfield, Mass. June 21, 1945.
  - Annie F. Foss to Mrs. Kreider., [1946] Oct.14; Item 87 (Box 1)
    Thanks for book of poems. ANS, card. Cover postmarked Pittsfield, Mass. Oct. 15, 1946.
  - Constance [Praeger Fox] to Olive Percival., 1944 July 19; Item 88 (Box 1)
    TLS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Altadena, July 19, 1944.
    Enclosures: 3 pages typed poems, signed.
  - Abbie C. Hancock to Olive., 1945 Jan. 1; Item 89 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded blue note. Cover postmarked Ontario, Calif. Jan. 2, 1945.
  - Helena M. Hand to Dear Olive., [1945 Dec.]; Item 90 (Box 1)
    ANS on Christmas folder. Cover postmarked Paterson, N.J. Dec. 14, 1945.
  - Alice [___] to Olive., [1939 Mar.]; Item 91 (Box 1)
    ANS, 1 p. blue note. Cover postmarked San Francisco, Mar. 16, 1939.
  - Edith Hawthorne to "Dear Lovely Lady"., [1945 Dec.]; Item 92 (Box 1)
    ALS written inside Christmas folder. Cover postmarked San Francisco, Dec. 8, 1945.
  - Edith Hawthorne to Florence Kreider., 1945 Dec.15; Item 93 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked San Francisco Dec. 17, 1945.
  - Edith Hawthorne to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Jan 7.; Item 94 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked San Francisco Jan. 7, 1946.
  - Henderson, Janet M.N., Mary A. and Isabel R. to "Dear friend of the long-ago"., 1941 Mar.30; Item 95 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Los Angeles.
  - Peggy Hess to Olive Percival., 1944 Aug.12; Item 96 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked Brookline, Maine Aug. 12, 1944.
  - Margaret Wendell Hess to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Nov.12; Item 97 (Box 1)
    Thanks for book of poems. ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked Wayne, Pa. Nov. 11, 1946.
  - Danzo Kiyowara to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Aug. 22; Item 98 (Box 1)
    Thanks for book of poems. ALS, 2 p. Cover postmarked Los Angeles Aug. 23, 1946.
  - A.K [Alice Klauber] to Olive., 1943 Aug.25; Item 99 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded gray note. Cover postmarked San Diego Aug. 28, 1943.
  - Leda Klauber to Mrs. Kreider., [1946 Mar.]; Item 100 (Box 1)
    Thanks for candlesticks, etc. ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked La Jolla, Mar. 21, 1946.
  - Ethel Kurth to Miss Percival., 1944 Nov. 27; Item 101 (Box 1)
    TLS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked New York, Nov. 29, 1944.
  - Olive Burrows Lipton [Mrs. Elmer Lipton]., 1944 June 26; Item 102 (Box 1)
    ALS, written inside birthday greeting. Photo pasted on front of card. Cover postmarked Reynolds, Ill.
  - Isabel W. Lockwood to Mrs. Kreider., [1946] Feb.28.; Item 103 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked Pasadena, Mar. 1, 1946.
  - Jack [Masse] to Mrs. Kreider., [1945 Dec.]; Item 104 (Box 1)
    TLS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Santa Cruz, Calif. Dec. 13, 1945.
  - Jack [Masse] to "Dear Friend [Mrs. S. L. Kreider]., [1945 Oct.]; Item 105 (Box 1)
    ALS, 3 p. Cover postmarked Santa Cruz, Calif. Oct. 26, 1945.
  - Jessie M. Norris to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 Oct.28; Item 106 (Box 1)
    ALS, 4 p. blue. Cover postmarked Van Nuys, Oct. 29, 1945.
  - Helen Piersen to Olive., 1945 July 11; Item 107 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded. Enclosing business card and memorial folder. Cover postmarked Santa Monica July 12, 1945.
  - George Plank to Olive Percival., 1945 Jan.15; Item 108 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Jan. 16, 1945 Asheville, N.C.
  - George Plank to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 Mar.6; Item 109 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Asheville, N.C.
  - George Plank to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 Mar.10; Item 110 (Box 1)
  - George Plank to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 Apr.2; Item 111 (Box 1)
  - George Plank to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 Apr.23; Item 112 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded. Cover postmarked Asheville, N. C. Apr. 23, 1945.
  - George Plank to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 May 18.; Item 113 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded. Carlisle, Pa.
  - George Plank to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Feb.4; Item 114 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded. Cover postmarked Five Ashes Tunbridge Wells, Feb. 5, 1946.
  - George Plank to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Mar. 6; Item 115 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked London, March 7, 1946.
  - Amy Plank Cocke to Miss Kreider., 1946 Aug. 19; Item 116 (Box 1)
    Thanks for book of poems. ALS, 1 p. folded. Cover postmarked Asheville Aug.20, 1946.
  - Francis Foote Riley to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Jan.27; Item 117 (Box 1)
    ALS, 2 p. Cover postmarked San Diego Jan 28, 1946.
  - Olive Percival to Marian Owen Ryan., 1942 Feb.5; Item 118 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Encl. photograph of young girl, dated in pencil on back by OP "Abt./1900 inscribed on front, ink "Lovingly/Missie". Cover postmarked Los Angeles and returned with note: Moved, left no address.
  - Missie" [Marion O. Ryan] to "Olive dean", [1943 Dec.] "; Item 119 (Box 1)
    ALS, 4 p. Cover postmarked Coronado, Dec. 1, 1943.
  - Missie" [Marion O. Ryan] to "Olive dear.", 1944 Jan.11 "; Item 120 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded blue note. Cover postmarked Coronado, Jan. 12, 1944.
  - Marion Owen Ryan to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 May 21; Item 121 (Box 1)
    ALS, 2 p.,purple ink. Cover postmarked San Diego May 21, 1945.
  - Marion Owen Ryan to Mrs. Kreider., 1945 Sept.5; Item 122 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p., purple ink. Cover postmarked Coronado, Sep. 6, 1945.
  - Bula Shrouf to "My Very Dear Friend" [Olive Percival], 1941 Dec. 31; Item 123 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Lucerne Valley, Dec. 31, 1941.
  - Bula [Shrouf] to "My Very Dear Friend" [Olive Percival], [1942 Sep.]; Item 124 (Box 1)
    ALS, 3 p. Cover postmarked Lucerne Valley, Sep. 11, 1942.
  - Bula Shrouf to "My Very Dear Friend" [Olive Percival], 1943 Feb.8; Item 125 (Box 1)
    ALS, 4 p. encl. 2 photos - 1 of desert, 1 of Mrs. Shrouf sitting on fallen Joshua tree in desert. Cover postmarked Lucerne Valley.
  - Alice Sm [Smith] to Olive., 1944 July 18.; Item 126 (Box 1)
    ALS, 2 p. Cover postmarked Philadelphia, Jul. 18, 1944.
  - Alice Sm [Smith] to Olive., [1945] Jan.20; Item 127 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Philadelphia, Jan 21, 1945.
  - Alice R. Smith to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Mar.2; Item 128 (Box 1)
    Thanks for parcel. Cover postmarked Philadelphia Mar 2, 1946. ALS, 1 p.
  - Alice R. Smith to Mrs. Kreider., [1946] Mar.11; Item 129 (Box 1)
    Cover postmarked Philadelphia Mar. 11, 1946. ALS, 1 p.
  - Elsie [Mrs. N. Sparling] to Olive., 1944 Apr. 1; Item 130 (Box 1)
    ALS, 3 p. Cover postmarked Emsworth, Hants, Apr. 2, 1944.
  - Elsie [Mrs. N. Sparling] to Olive., 1944 Nov.18; Item 131 (Box 1)
    ALS, 2 p. Cover postmarked Brighton & Hove, Sussex.
  - Elsie [Mrs. N. Sparling] to Olive., 1945 Jan. 2; Item 132 (Box 1)
    ALS, 2 p. Cover postmarked Worthing, Sussex, Jan. 4, 1945.
  - Elsie H. Sparling to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Mar.5; Item 133; ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked. (Box 1)
  - Elsie Halliday Sparling to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Sep.25; Item 134; ALS, 1 p. Cover. (Box 1)
    [Note written in ink on slip of white paper: Mr. & Mrs. Sparling were dear friends of O.P. Mrs. Sparling's first husband was Wm Morris I think.]
  - Evelyn Strout to Miss Percival., 1944 Feb. 11; Item 135 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked Teaneck, N. J. Feb. 13, 1944. (Note, ink, on cover: Insurance Associate.)
  - Pauline Stone Summers to Olive Percival., n.d.; Item 136 (Box 1)
    ANS, written on Christmas folder. Cover.
  - Pauline Stone Summers [Mrs. Dudley G. Summers] to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Aug. 27; Item 137 (Box 1)
    Thanks for "Yellowing Ivy." ALS, 1 p. Cover postmarked Woodstock, N. Y. [Note, ink, on cover: Wilbur Macy Stone's daughter. Mr. Stone was one of O.P's dearest friends.]
  - Elizabeth Waggoner to Mrs. Kreider., [1946 Oct.]; Item 138 (Box 1)
    Thanks for poems. ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked Los Angeles, Calif. Oct. 26, 1946.
  - Louise Ward Watkins to Mrs. Kreider., 1946 Aug. 12.; Item 139 (Box 1)
    Thanks for "Yellowing Ivy." ALS, 1 p. Folded note. Cover postmarked Pasadena.
  - Lila [Williams] to Olive., 1944 Jan. 5; Item 140 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked San Diego, Jan. 6, 1944.
  - 1945 Mar. 28., Item 141 (Box 1)
    Lila Williams to Mrs. Kreider. ALS, 1 p. folded note. Cover postmarked San Diego.
  - Janice (?) C. Lee to [Olive Percival]., n.d.; Item 142 (Box 1)
    ALS, 1 p. numbered 4. First 3 pages missing. At bottom of sheet under signature OP has written, ink: "Big Sister of my first Playmate/(Jany.-1922)"
    See also:
    Missing Title
    Miscellaneous 119/12/7 second item
    Miscellaneous 119/12/10 - 11 notes OP to Mrs. Wright
    Bookplates and Prints 119/18/42 Christmas cards
- 4. Manuscripts., (including typescripts)
  - Anthology of modern verse., Item 1 (Box 1)
    Typescript, inscribed on back cover "Anthology of Modern Verse" "Olive Percival" "1916 No. 1." Three newspaper clippings laid in. Poems arranged alphabetically, one to a page. In book form, [118 l.], 26 cm.
  - At eighteen., Item 2 (Box 5)
    Typescript on one sheet (8 1/2 × 7) of poem entitled "At Eighteen" consisting of five stanzas [4 lines each]. At lower left is typed: "Olive Percival." Also a carbon copy.
  - At eighteen., Item 3 (Box 5)
    Typescript on one sheet (8 1/2 × 7 1/2) of poem entitled "At Eighteen --" At lower left is typed: "Olive Percival/May/1938--"
  - At eighteen., Item 4 (Box 5)
    Typescript (carbon), on one sheet (8 1/2 × 11) of poem entitled "At Eighteen". At bottom left is typed: "Olive Percival/1938"
  - At eighteen., Item 5 (Box 5)
    Typescript (carbon), on one sheet (8 1/2 × 11) of poem entitled "At Eighteen"
    At bottom left is typed: "Olive Percival/May/1938 --"
    At bottom of page OP has written, ink, two lists of names.
    At end of the list appears: "8/16/38 Coronet (Albert Gingrich Ed. c/o Coronet 919 No. Michigan Ave., Chicago."
  - At eighteen., Item 6 (Box 5)
    Typescript (carbon), two copies (8 1/2 × 11), of poem entitled "At Eighteen."
    At bottom left is typed: "Olive Percival/522 San Pascual Avenue/Los Angeles -."
    At bottom of one copy OP has written, ink: "9/20/39 Sat. Ev. Post."
  - Children's bookplates., Item 7 (Box 5)
    Typescript, two sheets (8 1/2 × 11), entitled "Children's Bookplates." Signed, ink, by Olive Percival. OP has written title, ink, back of p. 2. Envelope.
  - Children's bookplates., Item 8 (Box 5)
    Typescript (blue carbon), four sheets (8 1/2 × 1) entitled "Children's Bookplates." "(Olive Percival)" typed at end of the article.
    Also typescript of page one of this article.
    At upper right Op has written, ink, "Return Postage Herewith 16¢."
  - Children's books of, 1805.; Item 9 (Box 5)
    Typescript, nine sheets (8 1/2 × 13), entitled "Children's books of 1805." Signed, ink, by Olive Percival.
    Changes and corrections, ink and pencil.
    Typed at top of first page "The Friday Morning Club/24 November, 1905."
    Title and date written, ink, on back of page nine.
    Seven names listed, pencil, back page nine.
  - The Christmas card drawings of George Wolfe Plank., Item 10 (Box 5)
    Typescript (blue carbon), four sheets (8 1/2 × 13) entitle "The Christmas Card Drawings of George Wolfe Plank".
    "(Olive Percival)" typed at end of article.
    Notation "Pub. in House Beautiful" in ink on back of page four.
  - Christopher Columbus and his four voyages., Item 11 (Box 5)
    Written by OP, red ink, three sheets (20 × 12 1/2 cm.) ruled paper.
    Two sheets written on both sides.
    Titled: "Christopher Columbus and his four voyages. Essay by Olive May Percival to be read May 25-'81. Commenced May 11. Ended May 18."
    Manuscript in portfolio, red and white paper, stylized design decorated inside and out with cut-out bell-shaped paper inscribed, ink, with memories of the school and teacher, Eda S. Dessau, May 1881.
  - Concerning music plates., Item 12 (Box 5)
    Typescript (carbon), six sheets (8 1/2 × 11) entitled "Concerning Music Plates."
    Typed at end of article "(Olive Percival)".
    OP has written, ink, on back of sheet six "Music Plates - (Written for A. F's Quarterly)".
  - The Down-hyl Claim - (The Garden)., Item 13 (Box 5)
    Typescript, seven sheets (8 1/2 × 13) entitled "The Down-hyl Claim. - (The Garden)". "Olive Percival)" typed at end of article.
    First page is original, others blue carbons.
    Some corrections and notes in ink. Written by OP, ink, on back of page seven "The Down-hyl Claim/The Garden/(Pub. in House Beautiful)/(City Water 1917."
  - The Down-hyl Claim - (The House)., Item 14 (Box 5)
    Typescript (blue carbon), eight pages (8 1/2 × 13) entitled "The Down-hyl Glaim - (The House)." "(Olive Percival)" typed at end of article.
    Corrections noted in ink.
    Written by OP, ink, on back of page eight "The Down-hyl Claim/The House/(Pub. in House Beautiful)." Pages seven and eight torn, mounted on other sheets.
  - In pursuit of the antique in modern New England., Item 15 (Box 5)
    Typescript, 19 sheets (8 1/2 × 13) entitled "In Pursuit of the Antique in Modern New England." Signed by OP, ink, at end.
    Typed at top of the first page "(Read before The Friday Morning Club of Los Angeles, March 18, 1904.)"
    Title and date written, ink, on back of page 19.
  - Japanese poems; fireflies, butterflies, dragon flies., Item 16 (Box 5)
    Manuscript, in ink, entitled "Japanese Poems/Fireflies/Butterflies/Dragon Flies/Copied by Olive Percival/1911."
    Cover inscribed with title and name.
    One poem copied on each sheet of double paper, Japanese style, reading from back to front; mounted in paper cover, book form. [23] double 1. 21 cm.
    Small square of wall-paper laid in on which OP has written, ink, a poem with name of author and date.
  - Japanese poems; love., Item 17 (Box 5)
    Manuscript, in ink, entitled "Japanese Poems/Love/Copied By Olive Percival/1911."
    Cover inscribed in same manner.
    One poem copied on each sheet of double paper, Japanese style, reading back to front; mounted in paper cover, book form. [22] double 1. 21cm.
  - Japanese poems; third book., Item 18 (Box 5)
    Manuscript, in ink, entitled "Japanese Poems/Third Book/Copied by Olive Percival/Los Angeles/1911."